AALIYAH MOTALA

DATA ANALYST

Contact

+27 83 667 6639

aaliyahmotala@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

Website

Skills

Python

SQL

R Software

Tableau

Power BI

Problem-solving

Communication

Project Management

Leadership and Teamwork

Attention To Detail

Languages

English

• • • • •

Afrikaans

••••

Chinese

• • • • •

Summary

Passionate data analyst that is adept at analyzing data from multiple data mediums such as Access, SQL, and Python. Bringing forth the ability to visualize information with Excel and Tableau. Experienced in preparing detailed documents and reports as well as interacting effectively with colleagues and clients

Education

Data Analyst Nanodegree

ALX-Udacity | August 2022 - October 2022

BSc Biological Science Honours

University of KwaZulu-Natal | Feb 2014 - Apr 2019

Certifications

Microsoft Power BI Data Analyst

Microsoft PL-300 Exam

Courses

Data Analyst - Excel & Tableau

EntryLevel | June 2022 - July 2022

Data Analyst - SQL

EntryLevel | July 2022 - August 2022

Data Analyst - Advanced SQL

EntryLevel | August 2022 - October 2022

Work Experience

Data Analyst

Vantage Data | November 2022 - present

- Created and provided support on PowerApps
- Designed and managed Alteryx Workflows
- Assisted with SnowFlake ETL uploads and management
- Created and managed Tableau and PowerBI reports
- Liaise with and update clients
- Create, troubleshoot and manage SQL and Python workflows and scripts

Clinical Trial Recruiter

Subjectwell | August 2021 - December 2021

Research Assistant

University of KwaZulu-Natal | May 2021 - August 2021

- Undertook and planned fieldwork
- Created a database of findings
- Created a GIS layer using Google Earth
- Analyzed findings with R software

Laboratory Demonstrator

University of KwaZulu-Natal | March 2021 - July 2021